Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: Personalities [includes color photographs], 1930s - 1970s; 5 (Box 1555)
    - World Adventure Series, Detroit, George F. Pierrot Lowell Thomas, principal speaker at a 1973 Detroit Press Club dinner commemorating the 40th birthday of the World Adventure Series, greets his friend George Pierrot, who founded the Series at Detroit's civic art museum in 1933. Thomas has been a member of the Series Board of Directors since its founding. Thomas, in behalf of friends and associates, presented Pierrot the portrait shown in the background, painted by the noted artist John Coppin. The World Adventure Series pioneered travel-adventure color movies in auditoriums and on television and has won many world-wide awards. The Detroit Press Club dinner was arranged by Leonard R. Barnes, author, world traveler and editor of Michigan AAA's monthly travel magazine, MICHIGAN LIVING, 22
    - Verso: World Adventure Series, Detroit, George F. Pierrot Lowell Thomas, principal speaker at a 1973 Detroit Press Club dinner commemorating the 40th birthday of the World Adventure Series, greets his friend George Pierrot, who founded the Series at Detroit's civic art museum in 1933. Thomas has been a member of the Series Board of Directors since its founding. Thomas, in behalf of friends and associates, presented Pierrot the portrait shown in the background, painted by the noted artist John Coppin. The World Adventure Series pioneered travel-adventure color movies in auditoriums and on television and has won many world-wide awards. The Detroit Press Club dinner was arranged by Leonard R. Barnes, author, world traveler and editor of Michigan AAA's monthly travel magazine, MICHIGAN LIVING, 22-verso
    - Lowell Thomas - George Pierrot Detriot Press Club, Nov. 1973; Lowell Thomas, a director of Detroit's World Adventure Series since its founding in 1933, came out to the Detroit Press Club in November, 1973 to celebrate the fortieth birthday of the Series, at a party honoring George F. Pierrot, the Series' founder. Lowell Thomas and George Pierrot are shown at the speakers' table. In the background in his portrait presented to Pierrot, by the noted artist John Coppin, of Florida, Bloomfield Hills, Michigan, and Bayfield, Ontario, 23
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas - George Pierrot Detriot Press Club, Nov. 1973; Lowell Thomas, a director of Detroit's World Adventure Series since its founding in 1933, came out to the Detroit Press Club in November, 1973 to celebrate the fortieth birthday of the Series, at a party honoring George F. Pierrot, the Series' founder. Lowell Thomas and George Pierrot are shown at the speakers' table. In the background in his portrait presented to Pierrot, by the noted artist John Coppin, of Florida, Bloomfield Hills, Michigan, and Bayfield, Ontario, 23-verso
    - Russell Chapman, General Secretary, Advertising Association of Great Britain with Lowell Thomas, President, Advertising Club of New York, Photographed on the occasion of SUPER-SALESMEN DAY Luncheon, Thursday, December 9, at the ADVERTISING CLUB OF NEW YORK, 24
    - Verso: Russell Chapman, General Secretary, Advertising Association of Great Britain with Lowell Thomas, President, Advertising Club of New York, Photographed on the occasion of SUPER-SALESMEN DAY Luncheon, Thursday, December 9, at the ADVERTISING CLUB OF NEW YORK, 24-verso
    - Caption: Joe Girard, World's No. 1 Automobile and Truck Retail Salesman 10 Consecutive Years, Lowell Thomas; One of the proudest moments of my life, [signed] Joe Girard, 25
    - LT, Jack Anderson, 26
    - Verso: LT, Jack Anderson, 26-verso
    - Jam Handy, 27
    - Verso: Jam Handy, 27-verso
    - Jam Handy, 28
    - Verso: Jam Handy, 28-verso
    - Jam Handy, 29
    - Verso: Jam Handy, 29-verso
    - Ali Khan, seated. LT and Col. Eddie Eagen, former heavyweight champion of the world. -amateur-, 30
    - Verso: Ali Khan, seated. LT and Col. Eddie Eagen, former heavyweight champion of the world. -amateur-, 30-verso
    - John Henry Falk, 31
    - Verso: John Henry Falk, 31-verso
    - Take to town and give to Joe Dougherty?, 32
    - Verso: Take to town and give to Joe Dougherty?, 32-verso
    - This was redone in semi-[?] for Caplities[?] office, 33
    - Verso: This was redone in semi-[?] for Caplities[?] office, 33-verso
  - Subject files: Personalities, circa 1930s - 1970s; 6 (Box 1555)
    - Dr. Isabel V. Sawhill, Director, National Commission for Employment Policy, Mr. Lowell Thomas, 1
    - Note: Dr. Isabel V. Sawhill, Director, National Commission for Employment Policy, Mr. Lowell Thomas, 2
    - Bruce Rismiller, President FSAA, J.Paul Lyet, Chairman and CEO Sperry Rand Corporation, Dr. Isabel V. Sawhill, Director National Commission for Employment Policy, W. M. Ellinghaus, President AT&T, Lowell Thomas, John A. Gambling, WOR Radio, 3
    - Note: Bruce Rismiller, President FSAA, J.Paul Lyet, Chairman and CEO Sperry Rand Corporation, Dr. Isabel V. Sawhill, Director National Commission for Employment Policy, W. M. Ellinghaus, President AT&T, Lowell Thomas, John A. Gambling, WOR Radio, 4
    - Franklin Maisano, President, Manhattan Life Insurance Co., E. L. Hennessey, Jr., Senior Vice President, United Technologies, C. W. Moritz, Vice Chairman, Dun & Bradstreet, Lowell Thomas, 5
    - Note: Franklin Maisano, President, Manhattan Life Insurance Co., E. L. Hennessey, Jr., Senior Vice President, United Technologies, C. W. Moritz, Vice Chairman, Dun & Bradstreet, Lowell Thomas, 6
    - Bruce Rismiller, President, FSAA; John A. Gambling, WOR Radio; J. Paul Lyet, Chairman and CEO, Sperry Rand Corporation; Dr. Isabel V. Sawhill, Direction National Commission for Employment Policy; W. M. Ellinghaus, President, AT&T; Jerome H. Holland, Former Ambassador to Sweden; Lowell Thomas; Rene C. McPherson, Chairman and CEO, Dana Corporation, 7
    - Note: Bruce Rismiller, President, FSAA; John A. Gambling, WOR Radio; J. Paul Lyet, Chairman and CEO, Sperry Rand Corporation; Dr. Isabel V. Sawhill, Direction National Commission for Employment Policy; W. M. Ellinghaus, President, AT&T; Jerome H. Holland, Former Ambassador to Sweden; Lowell Thomas; Rene C. McPherson, Chairman and CEO, Dana Corporation, 8
    - Joe Connolly, King Features, 9
    - Verso: Joe Connolly, King Features, 9-verso
    - Jack McCord, 10
    - Verso: Jack McCord, 10-verso
    - Mrs. [Boomer?], Fred Clark, 11
    - Verso: Mrs. [Boomer?], Fred Clark, 11-verso
    - Crowning a beauty queen, in Wash. D.C., 12
    - Verso: Crowning a beauty queen, in Wash. D.C., 12-verso
    - [Crowning a beauty queen, in Wash. D.C.], 13
    - Sir Edmund Hillary, 14
    - Verso: Sir Edmund Hillary, 14-verso
    - Prof. Harold Vinacke, Univ. of Cincinnati, 15
    - Verso: Prof. Harold Vinacke, Univ. of Cincinnati, 15-verso
    - Prof. Harold Vinacke, 16
    - Verso: Prof. Harold Vinacke, 16-verso
    - G.L. Phillipe, Pres. of General Electric and LT, 17
    - Verso: G.L. Phillipe, Pres. of General Electric and LT, 17-verso
    - LT Sr., Pres. John Dickey of Dartmouth, 18
    - Verso: LT Sr., Pres. John Dickey of Dartmouth, 18-verso
    - Harry C. Denny, and L.T., both on-time editors of the Victor Daily Record. H.C.D. later ed. of The Cripple Creek Times, 19
    - Verso: Harry C. Denny, and L.T., both on-time editors of the Victor Daily Record. H.C.D. later ed. of The Cripple Creek Times, 19-verso
    - Bill Van Dusen [Deusen?], right, ? left, 20
    - Note: Bill Van Dusen [Deusen?], right, ? left, 21
    - C [Hall?], 22
    - Verso: C [Hall?], 22-verso
    - C [Hall?], 23
    - C [Hall?], 24
    - LOWELL THOMAS RECEIVES AMERICAN LEGION PUBLIC RELATIONS AWARD - Veteran reporter and commentator Lowell Thomas is presented the 1972 American Legion National Commander's Public Relations Award by National Commander John H. Geiger, of Des Plaines, Ill., at the Legion's annual Public Relations Luncheon held March 1, 1972. Newsman Thomas was cited for "his pioneering efforts in the audio visual field as a commentator and lecturer on our world" and for bringing to the people of the world "a greater understanding of diverse lands and cultures." The Legion's Public Relations Luncheon was held in conjunction with the organization's 12th annual Washington Conference, February 27 - March 3. L to R: Ralph Bates, Aide to the National Commander; James C. Watkins, Legion Director of Public Relations; The Rev. Edward L. R. Elson, Chaplain of the Senate, Lowell Thomas., 25
    - Verso: LOWELL THOMAS RECEIVES AMERICAN LEGION PUBLIC RELATIONS AWARD - Veteran reporter and commentator Lowell Thomas is presented the 1972 American Legion National Commander's Public Relations Award by National Commander John H. Geiger, of Des Plaines, Ill., at the Legion's annual Public Relations Luncheon held March 1, 1972. Newsman Thomas was cited for "his pioneering efforts in the audio visual field as a commentator and lecturer on our world" and for bringing to the people of the world "a greater understanding of diverse lands and cultures." The Legion's Public Relations Luncheon was held in conjunction with the organization's 12th annual Washington Conference, February 27 - March 3. L to R: Ralph Bates, Aide to the National Commander; James C. Watkins, Legion Director of Public Relations; The Rev. Edward L. R. Elson, Chaplain of the Senate, Lowell Thomas., 25-verso
    - "the fish I caught was - yea long - or maybe longer" said LT to Dr. Fred McGinnis, Pres. Alaska Methodist University, Anchorage, 26
    - Verso: "the fish I caught was - yea long - or maybe longer" said LT to Dr. Fred McGinnis, Pres. Alaska Methodist University, Anchorage, 26-verso
    - L to R: Bob Reeves, Lowell Thomas Sr. 6/2/1962, 27
    - Verso: L to R: Bob Reeves, Lowell Thomas Sr. 6/2/1962, 27-verso
    - With Lady Ribblesdale, 28
    - Verso: With Lady Ribblesdale, 28-verso
    - Joe and LT., 29
    - Verso: Joe and LT., 29-verso
    - Hack Miller, Desert News, 30
    - Verso: Hack Miller, Desert News, 30-verso
    - Art Linkletter, L.T.; Bill Lear, inventor, jet, 31
    - Verso: Art Linkletter, L.T.; Bill Lear, inventor, jet, 31-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas talking with a man], 32
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking hands with a man], 33
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with a man], 34
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man talking], 35
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to a man at the punch bowl], 36
    - [Lowell Thomas receiving an award], 37
    - [Lowell Thomas standing outside with a man], 38
  - Subject files: Personalities [includes color photographs], circa 1950s - 1970s; 7 (Box 1555)
    - [Christl Thalhammer, Lowell Thomas, Lowell Thomas, Jr., standing, left to right], 1
    - Bob Considine, Thalhammer + LT, 2
    - Verso: Bob Considine, Thalhammer + LT, 2-verso
    - [Christl Thalhammer, Lowell Thomas, Bob Considine], 3
    - [Christl Thalhammer, Lowell Thomas, Bob Considine], 4
    - [Christl Thalhammer, Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas, Lowell Thomas], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas and Christl Thalhammer, at right], 6
    - Illustration for Adventures with the New Guinea Headhunters; [Thelma Ritter, second from left, Lowell Thomas and Christl Thalhammer, at right], 7
    - Verso: Illustration for Adventures with the New Guinea Headhunters; [Thelma Ritter, second from left, Lowell Thomas and Christl Thalhammer, at right], 7-verso
    - [left to right: Lowell Thomas, unidentified man, James H. "Jimmy" Doolittle, Neil Armstrong], 8
    - [left to right: Lowell Thomas, unidentified man, James H. "Jimmy" Doolittle, Neil Armstrong], 9
    - Verso: LT, ?, Doolittle, Neil Armstrong + ?, 9-verso
    - [left to right: unidentified man, Lowell Thomas, unidentified man, James H. "Jimmy" Doolittle, Neil Armstrong], 10
    - [left to right: unidentified man, Lowell Thomas, unidentified man, James H. "Jimmy" Doolittle, Neil Armstrong], 11
    - [left to right: unidentified man, Lowell Thomas, unidentified man, James H. "Jimmy" Doolittle], 12
    - Dec 23, 1961 [Lowell Thomas, Jr., left, Lowell Thomas, right], 13
    - Verso: Dec 23, 1961 [Lowell Thomas, Jr., left, Lowell Thomas, right], 13-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas, Jr., left, Lowell Thomas, right], 14
    - [Lowell Thomas, Mrs. Marianna Thomas, at right], 15
    - [Lowell Thomas standing in front of a drawing of a man], 16
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man], 17
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with a woman], 18
    - [Lowell Thomas and a woman reading from cards], 19
    - [Lowell Thomas and two men talking; wearing "Out Choice Lowell Thomas" ribbons], 20
    - [Lowell Thomas and two others on a ship], 21
    - [A man and a woman sitting at a banquet table], 22
    - [Lowell Thomas being presented with an award], 23
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man standing in front of a sign reading: "Manitou and Wheel Route (?) Peak RY.], 24
    - [Lowell Thomas standing in a group of men at an event, 25
  Box 1556
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: Personalities [includes color photographs], circa 1950s - 1970s; 1 (Box 1556)
    - Admiral Hyman Rickover and LT; man in middle is Dan Moore, director of the International Platform Association, 1
    - Verso: Admiral Hyman Rickover and LT; man in middle is Dan Moore, director of the International Platform Association, 1-verso
    - Caption: To my good friend Lowell Thomas I Like You! Enthusiastically, [signed] Joe [?], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with some men], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas, Mrs. Thomas, and two others standing in front of a NCA plane], 4
    - [A man standing under the wing of a plane], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking a man's hand], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man shaking hands], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting at a banquet table as someone delivers a speech], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man standing in front of a portrait], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man stanging in front of a painting], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man sitting in a lobby], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas with two men], 12
    - [Lowell Thomas delivering a speech at a school event (?)], 13
    - [Lowell Thomas and another man sitting at a banquet table], 14
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking hands with a man at the podium], 15
    - [Lowell Thomas interviewing (?) a man], 16
    - [Lowell Thomas receiving an award], 17
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting at a banquet table as someone gives a speech], 18
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting on a televison set. Note: "Working with tou have been the highlihgt of my career. Thanks, Jenny (?)"], 19
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with a woman], 20
    - [Lowell Thomas and two men at an event], 21
    - [Lowell Thomas and two other men], 22
    - [Lowell Thomas skiing with a friend], 23
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking hands with a woman at a ski mountain], 24
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with two men at a ski mountain], 25
    - [Lowell Thomas and a young man], 26
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with an officer], 27
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting at a table with other men], 28
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with three men at an event], 29
    - [Lowell Thomas walking with a man], 30
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with two men], 31
    - [Lowell Thomas standing while another men applauds], 32
  - Subject files: Gary Player, undated; 2 (Box 1556)
    - [Gary Player], 1
    - Verso: 9. Gary Player, 1-verso
  - Subject files: Polk Bros., 1956; 3 (Box 1556)
    - [Lowell Thomas, Jr and Lowell Thomas, left to right], 1
    - Note: [letter to Lowell Thomas from the Public Relations Director of Polk Bros.], 2
  - Subject files: Pole to Pole (airplane flight by Lowell Thomas, Jr.) [contact sheets], circa 1966; 4 (Box 1556)
    - Note: [Letter to Lowell Thomas from Dorothy F. Furman, President of Furman Associates concerning proof sheerts of photos taken on the Rockwell Polar Flight by Jay Eyerman.], 1
    - Note: [Letter to Lowell Thomas from Dorothy F. Furman, President of Furman Associates responding to a request for prints], 2
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 3
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 4
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 5
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 6
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 7
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 8
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 9
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 10
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 11
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 12
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 13
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 14
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 15
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 16
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 17
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 18
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 19
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 20
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 21
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 22
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 23
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 24
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 25
    - [Photos of Lowell Thomas's airplane flight Pole to Pole], 26
    - [Members of Lowell Thomas's flight, Pole to Pole], 27
    - [Memebers of Lowell Thomas's flight, Pole to Pole], 28
  - Subject files: Winston Pote (photographer), undated; 5 (Box 1556)
    - Mrs. Stefansson (formerly his secretary!), 1
    - Verso: Mrs. Stefansson (formerly his secretary!), 1-verso
    - My first picture very poor light and no lamps; Brig. General O.S. Rolfe and Captain? from Washington in charge of army hour broadcast (December - 1942), 2
    - Verso: My first picture very poor light and no lamps; Brig. General O.S. Rolfe and Captain? from Washington in charge of army hour broadcast (December - 1942), 2-verso
    - Part of Camp Hale (9000 feet high), 3
    - Verso: Part of Camp Hale (9000 feet high), 3-verso
    - Air View - Camp Hale Col.; Looking toward Denver (Railroad and road at left), 4
    - Verso: Air View - Camp Hale Col.; Looking toward Denver (Railroad and road at left), 4-verso
    - Me and a regular army major (minor + major) from Washington; Summit of Hoonestack Peak - January 1943; 13,000 feet; I went up on skis, but others used snowshoes. Trooper who took the picture was guide from Montana and we called him - "Snowshoe Wilson"; skis were no good!; Nice run down, 5
    - Verso: Me and a regular army major (minor + major) from Washington; Summit of Hoonestack Peak - January 1943; 13,000 feet; I went up on skis, but others used snowshoes. Trooper who took the picture was guide from Montana and we called him - "Snowshoe Wilson"; skis were no good!; Nice run down, 5-verso
    - Showing Inferno ski race course (taken when snow depth made it possible to walk over trees), 6
    - Verso: Showing Inferno ski race course (taken when snow depth made it possible to walk over trees), 6-verso
    - This is how it looked to Toni Matt, 7
    - Verso: This is how it looked to Toni Matt, 7-verso
    - Snow houses at 11,500 feet, built by snowshoe soldiers from Camp Hale, Colo., 8
    - Verso: Snow houses at 11,500 feet, built by snowshoe soldiers from Camp Hale, Colo., 8-verso
    - Skijoring to Homestake Peak; J-15 snow vehicle; (great skiing!), 9
    - Verso: Skijoring to Homestake Peak; J-15 snow vehicle; (great skiing!), 9-verso
    - Ski Troops on parade (first at Camp Hale); (negative made from color film and enlarged), 10
    - Verso: Ski Troops on parade (first at Camp Hale); (negative made from color film and enlarged), 10-verso
    - Allis Chalmers entry in snow vehicle contest. Something new in 1942; (note skis); One of my jobs, with cameras, 11
    - Verso: Allis Chalmers entry in snow vehicle contest. Something new in 1942; (note skis); One of my jobs, with cameras, 11-verso
    - A new recruit - Luigi Toegure, 12
    - Verso: A new recruit - Luigi Toegure, 12-verso
  - Subject files: Bonney Powell, circa 1939; 6 (Box 1556)
    - Caption: For Lowell in memory of a grand cruise around South America --- [signed] Bonney Powell, 1
  - Subject files: Princeton, circa 1950s, 1980; 7 (Box 1556)
    - [photograph of Lowell Thomas, Hugh Scott Taylor, Dr. Harold Dobbs and unidentified man at Princeton dinner], 1
    - Note: [letter to Lowell Thomas from Sylvia Healy, daughter of Dr. Harold Dobbs (circa 1976) that came with photograph of Princeton dinner (7.1)], [PDF], 2
    - Note: [note from L.T. to Electra Nicks concerning photograph 7.1] The one I'm talking to is Hugh Scott Taylor ? The man on the other side of me is Dr. Harold Dodds, who at the time was President of Princeton. I guess I was presiding. I've forgotten what the occasion was except that it was in honor of Dr. Taylor - it may have been at the time of his retirement or it was when he received his knighthood from the King, 3
    - Princeton, N.J. June 7, 1980, 4
    - Verso: Princeton, N.J. June 7, 1980, 4-verso
    - Princeton, N.J. June 7, 1980, 5
    - Verso: Princeton, N.J. June 7, 1980, 5-verso
  - Subject files: Pulse luncheon, circa 1953 - 1957; 8 (Box 1556)
    - Bill Buckley, [Bill?] Hearst, Eddie Rickenbacker, Jim Farley; Atty. Gen. Herb Brownell and John Daly, 1
    - Verso: Bill Buckley, [Bill?] Hearst, Eddie Rickenbacker, Jim Farley; Atty. Gen. Herb Brownell and John Daly, 1-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to people at the Pulse luncheon], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas and others at the Pulse luncheon], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with people at the Pulse luncheon], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with men at the Pulse luncheon], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking hands with a man at the Pulse luncheon], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with a man at the Pulse luncheon], 7
  - Subject files: Quaker Hall, undated; 9 (Box 1556)
    - [Quaker Hall], 1
  - Subject files: Quaker Hill fireplace, undated; 10 (Box 1556)
    - [Quaker Hill fireplace], 1
  - Subject files: Quaker Hill school, circa early 1900s; 11 (Box 1556)
    - [Quaker Hill school], 1
    - [Quaker Hill school], 2
    - [Quaker Hill school], 3
    - [Quaker Hill school], 4
    - [Quaker Hill school], 5
    - [Quaker Hill school], 6
  - Subject files: Chips Rafferty, undated; 12 (Box 1556)
    - [Chips Rafferty], 1
    - [A little wooden shrine "O Maria"], 2
    - Note: Chips Rafferty, Australian movie actor, LT did 2 or 3 independent productions in Australia, New Guinea (not High Adventure), 3
  - Subject files: Rangertone, Inc., undated; 13 (Box 1556)
    - From Rangertone, Inc. 73 Winthrop St Newark, NJ, 1
    - Verso: From Rangertone, Inc. 73 Winthrop St Newark, NJ, 1-verso
  - Subject files: James Whitcomb Riley, 1914; 14 (Box 1556)
    - [signed(?) picture of James Whitcomb Riley], 1
    - Verso: James Whitcomb Riley; The first picture he has had taken in four years; L. J. Thomas, Princeton, New Jersey, 1-verso
    - James Whitcomb Riley; [?] Thomas, Princeton, N.J., 2
    - Verso: James Whitcomb Riley; [?] Thomas, Princeton, N.J., 2-verso
  - Subject files: Oral Roberts [includes color photographs], undated; 15 (Box 1556)
    - Caption: Lowell Thomas joins Oral Roberts for his next special "Oral Roberts in Alaska", 1
    - [advertisement for "Oral Roberts in Alaska" with special guest Lowell Thomas], 2
    - [L.T. and Oral Roberts standing in snow], 3
    - [L.T., Oral Roberts and unidentified woman on set], 4
  - Subject files: Henry W. Rogers, circa 1856; 16 (Box 1556)
    - [cover of The Oxford Academy Jubilee], 1
    - [prortrait of Henry W. Rogers], 2
  - Subject files: President Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Lowell Thomas, 1930s; 17 (Box 1556)